<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
	<channel>
		<title>Alternative Fuels News -- ScienceDaily</title>
		<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/news/matter_energy/alternative_fuels/</link>
		<description>Alternative fuel sources. From hydrogen cars and microbial fuel cells to break-throughs in bioconversion, browse the latest research in alternative fuels.</description>
		<language>en-us</language>
		<pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2020 12:48:29 EST</pubDate>
		<lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2020 12:48:29 EST</lastBuildDate>
		<ttl>60</ttl>
		<image>
			<title>Alternative Fuels News -- ScienceDaily</title>
			<url>https://www.sciencedaily.com/images/scidaily-logo-rss.png</url>
			<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/news/matter_energy/alternative_fuels/</link>
			<description>For more science news, visit ScienceDaily.</description>
		</image>
		<atom:link xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" href="https://www.sciencedaily.com/rss/matter_energy/alternative_fuels.xml" type="application/rss+xml" />
		<item>
			<title>Research creates hydrogen-producing living droplets, paving way for alternative future energy source</title>
			<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/11/201125091459.htm</link>
			<description>Scientists have built tiny droplet-based microbial factories that produce hydrogen, instead of oxygen, when exposed to daylight in air. <!-- more --></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 25 Nov 2020 09:14:59 EST</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/11/201125091459.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Stable catalysts for new energy</title>
			<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/11/201124123631.htm</link>
			<description>Looking for the perfect catalyst is not only about finding the right material, but also about its orientation. Depending on the direction in which a crystal is cut and which of its atoms it thus presents to the outside world on its surface, its behavior can change dramatically. <!-- more --></description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 24 Nov 2020 12:36:31 EST</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/11/201124123631.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Highly efficient, long-lasting electrocatalyst to boost hydrogen fuel production</title>
			<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/11/201120095900.htm</link>
			<description>Researchers have developed a highly efficient and long-lasting electrocatalyst for water oxidation using cobalt, iron, and a minimal amount of ruthenium. <!-- more --></description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 20 Nov 2020 09:59:00 EST</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/11/201120095900.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>New semiconductor coating may pave way for future green fuels</title>
			<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/11/201118141733.htm</link>
			<description>Hydrogen gas and methanol for fuel cells or as raw materials for the chemicals industry, for example, could be produced more sustainably using sunlight, a new study shows. In this study, researchers have developed a new coating material for semiconductors that may create new opportunities to produce fuels in processes that combine direct sunlight with electricity. <!-- more --></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 18 Nov 2020 14:17:33 EST</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/11/201118141733.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>New technique seamlessly converts ammonia to green hydrogen</title>
			<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/11/201118141718.htm</link>
			<description>Researchers have developed a highly effective, environmentally friendly method for converting ammonia into hydrogen. The new technique is a major step forward for enabling a zero-pollution, hydrogen-fueled economy. The idea of using ammonia as a carrier for hydrogen delivery has gained traction in recent years because ammonia is much easier to liquify than hydrogen and is therefore much easier to store and transport. This technological breakthrough overcomes several existing barriers to the production of clean hydrogen from ammonia. <!-- more --></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 18 Nov 2020 14:17:18 EST</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/11/201118141718.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Faster detection of photocatalyst-generated oxygen has big implications for clean energy</title>
			<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/11/201118092942.htm</link>
			<description>In the future, hydrogen produced from sunlight and water using photocatalysts could provide a source of clean energy. Researchers have developed a method to detect the oxygen produced from this water-splitting reaction 1000 times faster. This new method can be utilized to improve our understanding of artificial photosynthesis&#039; reaction mechanisms and could contribute towards the development and large-scale implementation of photocatalyst technology for producing hydrogen fuel. <!-- more --></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 18 Nov 2020 09:29:42 EST</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/11/201118092942.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Prototype fuel gauge for orbit</title>
			<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/11/201112134633.htm</link>
			<description>Liquids aren&#039;t as well behaved in space as they are on Earth. Inside a spacecraft, microgravity allows liquids to freely slosh and float about. This behavior has made fuel quantity in satellites difficult to pin down, but a new 3D-imaging fuel gauge could offer an ideal solution. <!-- more --></description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 12 Nov 2020 13:46:33 EST</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/11/201112134633.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Tips for making nanographene</title>
			<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/11/201111092932.htm</link>
			<description>Nanographene is a material that is anticipated to radically improve solar cells, fuel cells, LEDs and more. Typically the synthesis of this material has been imprecise and difficult to control. For the first time, researchers have discovered a simple way to gain precise control over the fabrication of nanographene. In doing so, they have shed light on the previously unclear chemical processes involved in nanographene production. <!-- more --></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2020 09:29:32 EST</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/11/201111092932.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>&#039;Green&#039; method for making pharmaceutical intermediates</title>
			<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/10/201030122547.htm</link>
			<description>Scientists develop cHAT to simplify the reduction of alkenes to more useful intermediate molecules for drugs and other useful chemical compounds. <!-- more --></description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 30 Oct 2020 12:25:47 EDT</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/10/201030122547.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Solar hydrogen: Let&#039;s consider the stability of photoelectrodes</title>
			<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/10/201026095407.htm</link>
			<description>Scientists have examined the corrosion processes of high-quality BiVO4 photoelectrodes using different state-of-the-art characterisation methods. The result is the first operando stability study of high-purity BiVO4 photoanodes during the photoelectrochemical oxygen evolution reaction (OER). This work shows how the stability of photoelectrodes and catalysts can be compared and enhanced in the future. <!-- more --></description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 26 Oct 2020 09:54:07 EDT</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/10/201026095407.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Hydrogen embrittlement creates complications for clean energy storage, transportation</title>
			<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/10/201006114309.htm</link>
			<description>Hydrogen is becoming a crucial pillar in the clean energy movement, and developing safe and cost-effective storage and transportation methods for it is essential but complicated, because hydrogen can cause brittleness in several metals including ferritic steel. Recent advancements provide insight into the embrittlement process and a review of various methods improves the understanding of the structure, property, and performance of ferritic steels subjected to mechanical loading in a hydrogen environment. <!-- more --></description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 11:43:09 EDT</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/10/201006114309.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Spinach: Good for Popeye and the planet</title>
			<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/10/201005122138.htm</link>
			<description>Spinach, when converted from its leafy, edible form into carbon nanosheets, acts as a catalyst for an oxygen reduction reaction in fuel cells and metal-air batteries. <!-- more --></description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 05 Oct 2020 12:21:38 EDT</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/10/201005122138.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Lego-like assembly of zeolitic membranes improves carbon capture</title>
			<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/10/201005112139.htm</link>
			<description>Chemical engineers have developed a new way to manufacture zeolitic membranes, state-of-the-art materials used for gas separation in harsh conditions. <!-- more --></description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 05 Oct 2020 11:21:39 EDT</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/10/201005112139.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Generating renewable hydrogen fuel from the sea</title>
			<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/09/200929173419.htm</link>
			<description>The power of the sun, wind and sea may soon combine to produce clean-burning hydrogen fuel, according to researchers. The team integrated water purification technology into a new proof-of-concept design for a sea water electrolyzer, which uses an electric current to split apart the hydrogen and oxygen in water molecules. <!-- more --></description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 29 Sep 2020 17:34:19 EDT</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/09/200929173419.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>New materials: A toggle switch for catalysis</title>
			<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/09/200923124604.htm</link>
			<description>A special material made of lanthanum, strontium, iron and oxygen can be switched back and forth between two different states: In one state the material is catalytically extremely active, in the other less so. The reason for this is the behavior of tiny iron nanoparticles on the surface. This finding should now make it possible to develop even better catalysts. <!-- more --></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 23 Sep 2020 12:46:04 EDT</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/09/200923124604.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>How to harness the power of biosolids to make hydrogen</title>
			<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/09/200914095901.htm</link>
			<description>New technology uses biosolids to drive the chemical reactions needed to produce hydrogen from biogas. The circular economy approach means all the materials needed for hydrogen production could be sourced on-site at a wastewater treatment plant, without the need for expensive catalysts. <!-- more --></description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 14 Sep 2020 09:59:01 EDT</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/09/200914095901.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>High-precision electrochemistry: The new gold standard in fuel cell catalyst development</title>
			<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/09/200910150340.htm</link>
			<description>Scientists have made a pivotal discovery that could extend the lifetime of fuel cells that power electric vehicles by eliminating the dissolution of platinum catalysts. <!-- more --></description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2020 15:03:40 EDT</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/09/200910150340.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>New nitrogen assembly carbon catalyst has potential to transform chemical manufacturing</title>
			<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/08/200826131857.htm</link>
			<description>Scientists have discovered a metal-free carbon-based catalyst that has the potential to be much less expensive and more efficient for many industrial concerns, including manufacturing of bio- and fossil fuels, electrocatalysis, and fuel cells. <!-- more --></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 26 Aug 2020 13:18:57 EDT</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/08/200826131857.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Sandwich catalysts offer higher activity and durability</title>
			<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/08/200826101633.htm</link>
			<description>A professor has developed a double-layered nanoporous platinum catalyst that activates hydrogen generation. <!-- more --></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 26 Aug 2020 10:16:33 EDT</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/08/200826101633.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Hydrochloric acid boosts catalyst activity</title>
			<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/08/200825110652.htm</link>
			<description>A research team has developed a synthesis process which drastically increases the activity of catalysts for the desulfurization of crude oil. The new process could perhaps also be used for catalysts in fuel cells. <!-- more --></description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 25 Aug 2020 11:06:52 EDT</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/08/200825110652.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Advanced biofuels show real promise for replacing some fossil fuels</title>
			<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/08/200824165632.htm</link>
			<description>A new study predicted significant climate benefits stemming from the use of advanced biofuel technologies. <!-- more --></description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 24 Aug 2020 16:56:32 EDT</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/08/200824165632.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Scientists get atomistic picture of platinum catalyst degradation</title>
			<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/08/200824165611.htm</link>
			<description>Degradation of platinum, used as a key electrode material in the hydrogen economy, severely shortens the lifetime of electrochemical energy conversion devices, such as fuel cells. For the first time, scientists elucidated the movements of the platinum atoms that lead to catalyst surface degradation. <!-- more --></description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 24 Aug 2020 16:56:11 EDT</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/08/200824165611.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Wireless device makes clean fuel from sunlight, CO2 and water</title>
			<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/08/200824123406.htm</link>
			<description>Researchers have developed a standalone device that converts sunlight, carbon dioxide and water into a carbon-neutral fuel, without requiring any additional components or electricity. <!-- more --></description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 24 Aug 2020 12:34:06 EDT</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/08/200824123406.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Fuel cells for hydrogen vehicles are becoming longer lasting</title>
			<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/08/200824123403.htm</link>
			<description>An international research team has succeeded in developing an electrocatalyst for hydrogen fuel cells which, in contrast to the catalysts commonly used today, does not require a carbon carrier and is therefore much more stable. The new process is industrially applicable and can be used to further optimize fuel cell powered vehicles without CO2 emissions. <!-- more --></description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 24 Aug 2020 12:34:03 EDT</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/08/200824123403.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Converting solar energy to hydrogen fuel, with help from photosynthesis</title>
			<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/08/200817104305.htm</link>
			<description>Global economic growth comes with increasing demand for energy, but stepping up energy production can be challenging. Recently, scientists have achieved record efficiency for solar-to-fuel conversion, and now they want to incorporate the machinery of photosynthesis to push it further. <!-- more --></description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 17 Aug 2020 10:43:05 EDT</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/08/200817104305.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>New kind of interaction discovered in hydrogen-producing enzymes</title>
			<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/08/200817104235.htm</link>
			<description>Hydrogenases can convert hydrogen just as efficiently as expensive platinum catalysts. In order to make them usable for biotechnological applications, researchers are deciphering how they work in detail. A team now reports that the transfer of protons and electrons by the enzyme takes place spatially separated, but is nevertheless coupled and thus, a decisive factor for efficiency. <!-- more --></description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 17 Aug 2020 10:42:35 EDT</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/08/200817104235.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Investigating a thermal challenge for metal organic frameworks</title>
			<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/08/200811120054.htm</link>
			<description>New research examines heat transfer in MOFs and the role it plays when MOFs are used for storing fuel. <!-- more --></description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 11 Aug 2020 12:00:54 EDT</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/08/200811120054.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Turning carbon dioxide into liquid fuel</title>
			<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/08/200805160947.htm</link>
			<description>Chemists report a new electrocatalyst that converts carbon dioxide and water into ethanol with very high energy efficiency, high selectivity for the desired final product and low cost. <!-- more --></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2020 16:09:47 EDT</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/08/200805160947.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Scientists develop new material for longer-lasting fuel cells</title>
			<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/07/200722192148.htm</link>
			<description>New research suggests that graphene -- made in a specific way -- could be used to make more durable hydrogen fuel cells for cars. <!-- more --></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2020 19:21:48 EDT</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/07/200722192148.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The secret to renewable solar fuels is an off-and-on again relationship</title>
			<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/07/200717101021.htm</link>
			<description>Copper that was once bound with oxygen is better at converting CO2 into renewable fuels than copper that was never bound to oxygen, according to scientists. <!-- more --></description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 17 Jul 2020 10:10:21 EDT</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/07/200717101021.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Low-cost catalyst helps turn seawater into fuel at scale</title>
			<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/07/200715123120.htm</link>
			<description>The Navy&#039;s quest to power its ships by converting seawater into fuel is one step nearer fruition. Chemical engineers have demonstrated that a potassium-promoted molybdenum carbide catalyst efficiently and reliably converts carbon dioxide to carbon monoxide, a critical step in the process. <!-- more --></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 15 Jul 2020 12:31:20 EDT</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/07/200715123120.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>New candidate for raw material synthesis through gene transfer</title>
			<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/07/200702113656.htm</link>
			<description>Cyanobacteria hardly need any nutrients and use the energy of sunlight. Bathers are familiar with these microorganisms as they often occur in waters. A group of researchers has discovered that the multicellular species Phormidium lacuna can be genetically modified by natural transformation and could thus produce substances such as ethanol or hydrogen. <!-- more --></description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 02 Jul 2020 11:36:56 EDT</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/07/200702113656.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>AI could help improve performance of lithium-ion batteries and fuel cells</title>
			<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/06/200625080942.htm</link>
			<description>Researchers have demonstrated how machine learning could help design lithium-ion batteries and fuel cells with better performance. <!-- more --></description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 25 Jun 2020 08:09:42 EDT</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/06/200625080942.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Engineers develop new fuel cells with twice the operating voltage as hydrogen</title>
			<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/06/200618092445.htm</link>
			<description>Engineers have developed high-power, direct borohydride fuel cells that operate at double the voltage of conventional hydrogen fuel cells. <!-- more --></description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 18 Jun 2020 09:24:45 EDT</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/06/200618092445.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Engineers find neat way to turn waste carbon dioxide into useful material</title>
			<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/06/200610152016.htm</link>
			<description>Making catalysts to convert waste carbon dioxide into useful industrial products has been expensive and complicated -- until now. Engineers show it&#039;s as easy as playing with Lego. <!-- more --></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 15:20:16 EDT</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/06/200610152016.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Researchers advance fuel cell technology</title>
			<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/06/200608092956.htm</link>
			<description>Researchers have made a key advance in solid oxide fuel cells (SOFCs) that could make the highly energy-efficient and low-polluting technology a more viable alternative to gasoline combustion engines for powering cars. <!-- more --></description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 08 Jun 2020 09:29:56 EDT</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/06/200608092956.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Solar hydrogen production: Splitting water with UV is now at almost 100% quantum efficiency</title>
			<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/06/200603104547.htm</link>
			<description>Scientists have successfully split water into hydrogen and oxygen using light and meticulously designed catalysts, and they did so at the maximum efficiency meaning there was almost no loss and undesired side reactions. This latest breakthrough in solar hydrogen production makes the likelihood of scalable, economically viable hydrogen production more than likely, paving the way for humanity to make the switch to clean energy. <!-- more --></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 03 Jun 2020 10:45:47 EDT</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/06/200603104547.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Electrolysis: Chemists have discovered how to produce better electrodes</title>
			<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/05/200514092547.htm</link>
			<description>Another step forward for renewable energies: The production of green hydrogen could be even more efficient in the future. By applying an unusual process step, chemists have found a way to treat inexpensive electrode materials and considerably improve their properties during electrolysis. <!-- more --></description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 14 May 2020 09:25:47 EDT</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/05/200514092547.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Room-temperature superionic conduction achieved using pseudorotation of hydride complexes</title>
			<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/05/200513111409.htm</link>
			<description>There is currently a strong demand to replace organic liquid electrolytes used in conventional rechargeable batteries, with solid-state ionic conductors which will enable the batteries to be safer and have higher energy density. <!-- more --></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 13 May 2020 11:14:09 EDT</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/05/200513111409.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Coordination polymer glass provides solid support for hydrogen fuel cells</title>
			<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/05/200513081812.htm</link>
			<description>Scientists are synthesizing stronger and more efficient materials for hydrogen fuel cell membranes. Most fuel cells currently on the market employ liquid membranes. A new coordination polymer glass membrane works just as well as its liquid counterparts with added strength and flexibility. <!-- more --></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 13 May 2020 08:18:12 EDT</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/05/200513081812.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The role of European policy for improving power plant fuel efficiency</title>
			<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/05/200508184601.htm</link>
			<description>A new study investigates the impact of the European Union Emissions Trading Scheme (EU ETS), the largest international cap-and-trade system for greenhouse gas emissions in the world, on power plant fuel efficiency. <!-- more --></description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 08 May 2020 18:46:01 EDT</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/05/200508184601.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Water-splitting module a source of perpetual energy</title>
			<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/05/200504150211.htm</link>
			<description>Researchers have integrated high-efficiency solar cells and electrode catalysts into an efficient, low-cost device that splits water to produce hydrogen fuel. <!-- more --></description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 04 May 2020 15:02:11 EDT</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/05/200504150211.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>User research at BESSY II: How new materials increase the efficiency of direct ethanol fuel cells</title>
			<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/05/200504113638.htm</link>
			<description>Researchers have investigated a novel composite membrane for ethanol fuel cells. It consists of the polymer Nafion, in which nanoparticles of a titanium compound are embedded by the rarely explored melt extrusion process. <!-- more --></description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 04 May 2020 11:36:38 EDT</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/05/200504113638.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Groundbreaking new rocket-propulsion system</title>
			<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/04/200430113007.htm</link>
			<description>Researchers have developed an advanced new rocket-propulsion system once thought to be impossible. The system, known as a rotating detonation rocket engine, will allow upper stage rockets for space missions to become lighter, travel farther, and burn more cleanly. <!-- more --></description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 11:30:07 EDT</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/04/200430113007.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Getting through the bottleneck -- A new class of layered perovskite with high oxygen-ion conductivity</title>
			<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/04/200427140503.htm</link>
			<description>Scientists have discovered a layered perovskite that shows unusually high oxide-ion conductivity, based on a new screening method and a new design concept. Such materials are hard to come by, so the discovery of this material, the new method and design concept will make the realization of many environment-friendly technologies. <!-- more --></description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2020 14:05:03 EDT</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/04/200427140503.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Researchers make key advance toward production of important biofuel</title>
			<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/04/200427140501.htm</link>
			<description>An international research collaboration has taken an important step toward the commercially viable manufacture of biobutanol, an alcohol whose strong potential as a fuel for gasoline-powered engines could pave the path away from fossil fuels. <!-- more --></description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2020 14:05:01 EDT</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/04/200427140501.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Advancing high temperature electrolysis: Splitting water to store energy as hydrogen</title>
			<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/04/200421134405.htm</link>
			<description>Recently, researchers developed a new electrode material for an electrochemical cell that can efficiently convert excess electricity and water into hydrogen. When demand for electricity increases, the electrochemical cell is reversible, converting hydrogen back into electricity for the grid. The hydrogen could also be used as fuel for heat, vehicles or other applications. <!-- more --></description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 21 Apr 2020 13:44:05 EDT</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/04/200421134405.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Gas storage method could help next-generation clean energy vehicles</title>
			<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/04/200416151739.htm</link>
			<description>A Northwestern University research team has designed and synthesized new materials with ultrahigh porosity and surface area for the storage of hydrogen and methane for fuel cell-powered vehicles. The materials, a type of a metal-organic framework (MOF), can store significantly more hydrogen and methane than conventional adsorbent materials at much safer pressures and at much lower costs. A one-gram sample of the material (with a volume of six M&amp;Ms) has a surface area that would cover 1.3 football fields. <!-- more --></description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 16 Apr 2020 15:17:39 EDT</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/04/200416151739.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>3D nanoparticles and magnetic spin</title>
			<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/04/200409105411.htm</link>
			<description>Researchers have captured 3D images of nanoparticles in liquid with atomic precision, and developed an ultrathin electrical switch that could further miniaturize computing devices and personal electronics without loss of performance. <!-- more --></description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2020 10:54:11 EDT</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/04/200409105411.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>&#039;Tequila&#039; powered biofuels more efficient than corn or sugar</title>
			<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/03/200331130108.htm</link>
			<description>Agave tequilana, the plant native to Mexico used to make tequila, could prove to be an efficient alternative to sugarcane and corn to make biofuels in semi-arid regions. This research is the first to look at the plants lifecycle and model the economics. <!-- more --></description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2020 13:01:08 EDT</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/03/200331130108.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Innovative thinner electrolyte can improve functioning of solid oxide fuel cells</title>
			<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/03/200325110917.htm</link>
			<description>Solid oxide fuel cells (SOFCs) are clean and highly efficient power generation systems, which can generate electrical energy but are limited by their high operating temperatures and infrequent applications. Researchers explore how the efficiency of SOFCs can be increased by lowering their operating temperature and could be an alternative to nuclear and thermal power generation in the future. <!-- more --></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 25 Mar 2020 11:09:17 EDT</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/03/200325110917.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>New material developed could help clean energy revolution</title>
			<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/03/200323112100.htm</link>
			<description>Researchers developed a promising graphene-carbon nanotube catalyst, giving them better control over hugely important chemical reactions for producing green technology and clean energy. <!-- more --></description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 23 Mar 2020 11:21:00 EDT</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/03/200323112100.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Nature-inspired green energy technology clears important development hurdle</title>
			<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/03/200319125121.htm</link>
			<description>A new material design has put the long-sought idea of using artificial photosynthesis to generate renewable fuel within reach. <!-- more --></description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 19 Mar 2020 12:51:21 EDT</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/03/200319125121.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Feeding fusion: Hydrogen ice pellets prove effective for fueling fusion plasmas</title>
			<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/03/200310164739.htm</link>
			<description>Injecting pellets of hydrogen ice rather than puffing hydrogen gas improves fusion performance. Studies by physicists compared the two methods on the DIII-D National Fusion Facility, looking ahead to the fueling to be used on ITER. <!-- more --></description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2020 16:47:39 EDT</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/03/200310164739.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>A novel biofuel system for hydrogen production from biomass</title>
			<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/03/200310094248.htm</link>
			<description>A recent study has presented a new biofuel system that uses lignin found in biomass for the production of hydrogen. <!-- more --></description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2020 09:42:48 EDT</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/03/200310094248.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Water splitting advance holds promise for affordable renewable energy</title>
			<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/03/200309130034.htm</link>
			<description>A team has developed a less expensive water electrolysis system that works under alkaline conditions but still produces hydrogen at comparable rates to the currently used system that works under acidic conditions and requires precious metals. This advance brings down the cost of water splitting technology, offering a more viable way to store energy from solar and wind power in the form of hydrogen fuel. <!-- more --></description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 09 Mar 2020 13:00:34 EDT</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/03/200309130034.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Micromotors get supercharged with three &#039;engines&#039;</title>
			<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/03/200304141504.htm</link>
			<description>Someday, microscopic robots could perform useful functions, such as diagnostic testing in lab-on-a-chip sensors, micropatterning surfaces or repairing equipment in tight spaces. But first, scientists need to be able to tightly control the microbots&#039; speed. Now, researchers have developed micromotors with three &#039;engines&#039; that they can control separately with chemical fuel, magnets and light. <!-- more --></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 04 Mar 2020 14:15:04 EST</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/03/200304141504.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>New method converts carbon dioxide to methane at low temperatures</title>
			<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/02/200227114523.htm</link>
			<description>Scientists developed a new method to convert carbon dioxide to methane with an electric field at low temperatures. In comparison to previous methods, this new method can produce any amount of methane whenever necessary. Because methane is a valuable gas which can be used to generate heat and electricity, this method could be exploited to help reduce the use of fossil fuels and prevent global warming. <!-- more --></description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2020 11:45:23 EST</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/02/200227114523.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Motley crew: Rust and light a possible answer to the conundrum of hydrogen fuel production</title>
			<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/02/200226131329.htm</link>
			<description>Production of hydrogen fuel is a key goal towards the development of sustainable energy practices, but this process does not have feasible techniques yet. Scientists have identified a novel technique of using rust and light to speed up hydrogen production from organic waste solution, a finding that can revolutionize the clean energy industry. <!-- more --></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2020 13:13:29 EST</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/02/200226131329.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Barriers to development of seawater electrolysis technologies</title>
			<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/02/200219113801.htm</link>
			<description>Researchers have identified the key technological and scientific challenges of producing hydrogen through seawater electrolysis. <!-- more --></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2020 11:38:01 EST</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/02/200219113801.htm</guid>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
<!-- Page successfully written to cache. -->
