<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
	<channel>
		<title>Batteries News -- ScienceDaily</title>
		<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/news/matter_energy/batteries/</link>
		<description>Read the latest research on everything from new longer life batteries and batteries with viruses to a nano-size battery.</description>
		<language>en-us</language>
		<pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2020 12:48:34 EST</pubDate>
		<lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2020 12:48:34 EST</lastBuildDate>
		<ttl>60</ttl>
		<image>
			<title>Batteries News -- ScienceDaily</title>
			<url>https://www.sciencedaily.com/images/scidaily-logo-rss.png</url>
			<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/news/matter_energy/batteries/</link>
			<description>For more science news, visit ScienceDaily.</description>
		</image>
		<atom:link xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" href="https://www.sciencedaily.com/rss/matter_energy/batteries.xml" type="application/rss+xml" />
		<item>
			<title>Creating higher energy density lithium-ion batteries for renewable energy applications</title>
			<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/11/201124111345.htm</link>
			<description>Lithium-ion batteries that function as high-performance power sources for renewable applications, such as electric vehicles and consumer electronics, require electrodes that deliver high energy density without compromising cell lifetimes. Researchers investigate the origins of degradation in high energy density LIB cathode materials and develop strategies for mitigating those degradation mechanisms and improving LIB performance. <!-- more --></description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 24 Nov 2020 11:13:45 EST</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/11/201124111345.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The ultimate conditions to get the most out of high-nickel batteries</title>
			<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/11/201118141748.htm</link>
			<description>It is common knowledge in battery manufacturing that many cathode materials are moisture sensitive. However, as the popularity of high nickel-based battery components increases, researchers have found that the drier the conditions that these cathodes are stored and processed in, then significant improvement in performance of the battery is gained. <!-- more --></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 18 Nov 2020 14:17:48 EST</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/11/201118141748.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>New technique seamlessly converts ammonia to green hydrogen</title>
			<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/11/201118141718.htm</link>
			<description>Researchers have developed a highly effective, environmentally friendly method for converting ammonia into hydrogen. The new technique is a major step forward for enabling a zero-pollution, hydrogen-fueled economy. The idea of using ammonia as a carrier for hydrogen delivery has gained traction in recent years because ammonia is much easier to liquify than hydrogen and is therefore much easier to store and transport. This technological breakthrough overcomes several existing barriers to the production of clean hydrogen from ammonia. <!-- more --></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 18 Nov 2020 14:17:18 EST</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/11/201118141718.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Printable, high-performance solid-state electrolyte films for next-generation batteries</title>
			<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/11/201118141717.htm</link>
			<description>A team has developed a new method of printing and sintering a variety of solid-state electrolyte thin films called &#039;printing and radiative heating.&#039; <!-- more --></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 18 Nov 2020 14:17:17 EST</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/11/201118141717.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Simple method to produce high performing lithium selenium batteries</title>
			<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/11/201116112902.htm</link>
			<description>Engineers have developed a simple and elegant method of producing high-powered lithium-selenium (Li-Se) batteries. <!-- more --></description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 16 Nov 2020 11:29:02 EST</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/11/201116112902.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Zinc-ion hybrid capacitors with ideal anions in the electrolyte show extra-long performance</title>
			<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/11/201113105838.htm</link>
			<description>Metal-ion hybrid capacitors combine the properties of capacitors and batteries. One electrode uses the capacitive mechanism, the other the battery-type redox processes. Scientists have now scrutinized the role of anions in the electrolyte. The results reveal the importance of sulfate anions. Sulfate-based electrolytes gave zinc-ion hybrid capacitors outstanding performance and extra-long operability. <!-- more --></description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 13 Nov 2020 10:58:38 EST</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/11/201113105838.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Environmentally friendly method could lower costs to recycle lithium-ion batteries</title>
			<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/11/201112144017.htm</link>
			<description>A new process for restoring spent cathodes to mint condition could make it more economical to recycle lithium-ion batteries. The process, developed by nanoengineers, is more environmentally friendly than today&#039;s methods; it uses greener ingredients, consumes 80 to 90% less energy, and emits about 75% less greenhouse gases. <!-- more --></description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 12 Nov 2020 14:40:17 EST</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/11/201112144017.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Improving high-energy lithium-ion batteries with carbon filler</title>
			<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/11/201110112518.htm</link>
			<description>Lithium-ion batteries are the major rechargeable power source for many portable devices as well as electric vehicles, but their use is limited, because they do not provide high power output while simultaneously allowing reversible energy storage. New research aims to offer a solution by showing how the inclusion of conductive fillers improves battery performance. <!-- more --></description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 10 Nov 2020 11:25:18 EST</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/11/201110112518.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Creating 3D virtual personas of all-solid-state batteries, building a better tomorrow</title>
			<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/11/201110102538.htm</link>
			<description>Scientists are eyeing all-solid-state-lithium batteries as a safer alternative to conventional lithium-ion batteries; but their performance needs much improvement. Now, with the 3D digital twin technology that a team from Korea has developed, a 3D digital replica of the real thing can be developed, and their solid interface microstructures can be studied in detail, potentially accelerating their advancement manifold. <!-- more --></description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 10 Nov 2020 10:25:38 EST</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/11/201110102538.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>New &#039;genomic&#039; method reveals atomic arrangements of battery material</title>
			<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/11/201109120646.htm</link>
			<description>Scientists have developed a new way to decipher the atomic-level structure of materials based on data gleaned from ground-up powder samples. They describe their approach and demonstrate its ability to solve the structure of a material that shows promise for shuttling ions through sodium-ion batteries. <!-- more --></description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2020 12:06:46 EST</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/11/201109120646.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>New technique extends next-generation lithium metal batteries</title>
			<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/11/201104114743.htm</link>
			<description>Engineering researchers have found that alkali metal additives, such as potassium ions, can prevent lithium microstructure proliferation during battery use. They used a combination of microscopy, nuclear magnetic resonance, and computational modeling to discover that adding small amounts of potassium salt to a conventional lithium battery electrolyte produces unique chemistry at the lithium/electrolyte interface, and modulates degradation during battery operation, preventing the growth of microstructures and leading to safer, longer lasting batteries. <!-- more --></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 04 Nov 2020 11:47:43 EST</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/11/201104114743.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>An underwater navigation system powered by sound</title>
			<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/11/201102110028.htm</link>
			<description>Underwater backscatter localization could allow for battery-free ocean exploration. The system is akin to subsea GPS and has potential applications in marine conservation, aquaculture, underwater robotics, and more. <!-- more --></description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2020 11:00:28 EST</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/11/201102110028.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Extending battery life in smartphones, electric cars</title>
			<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/10/201026114202.htm</link>
			<description>A researcher is working to make portable devices and electric vehicles stay charged longer by extending the life of the rechargeable lithium-ion batteries powering them. He is doing this by making the batteries more efficient, with some of his latest work focusing on keeping the anode from falling apart over time. <!-- more --></description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 26 Oct 2020 11:42:02 EDT</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/10/201026114202.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Charging electric cars up to 90% in 6 minutes</title>
			<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/10/201023095847.htm</link>
			<description>POSTECH Professor Byoungwoo Kang&#039;s research team uncovers a new Li-ion battery electrode material that can achieve high-energy density and high power capability per volume without reducing particle size. <!-- more --></description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 23 Oct 2020 09:58:47 EDT</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/10/201023095847.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Making disorder for an ideal battery</title>
			<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/10/201012171357.htm</link>
			<description>The lithium batteries that power our electronic devices and electric vehicles have a number of drawbacks. The electrolyte is a flammable liquid and the lithium they&#039;re made of is a limited resource. Specialists have now developed a non-flammable, solid electrolyte that operates at room temperature. It transports sodium - which is found everywhere on earth - instead of lithium. <!-- more --></description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 12 Oct 2020 17:13:57 EDT</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/10/201012171357.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Airdropping sensors from moths</title>
			<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/10/201008104257.htm</link>
			<description>Researchers have created a sensor system that can ride aboard a small drone or an insect, such as a moth, until it gets to its destination. <!-- more --></description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 08 Oct 2020 10:42:57 EDT</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/10/201008104257.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>New findings pave the way to environmentally friendly supercapacitors</title>
			<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/10/201007093622.htm</link>
			<description>Similar to batteries, supercapacitors are suitable for the repeated storage of electrical energy. Researchers have now presented a particularly safe and sustainable variant of such a supercapacitor. <!-- more --></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 07 Oct 2020 09:36:22 EDT</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/10/201007093622.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Ecological power storage battery made of vanillin</title>
			<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/10/201001090149.htm</link>
			<description>Researchers have found a way to convert the aromatic substance vanillin into a redox-active electrolyte material for liquid batteries. The technology is an important step towards ecologically sustainable energy storage. <!-- more --></description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2020 09:01:49 EDT</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/10/201001090149.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Battery fires: Industry and research must work together for safer batteries</title>
			<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/09/200923124609.htm</link>
			<description>Fire safety issues with lithium-ion batteries could be addressed with better collaboration across sectors, experts have said. <!-- more --></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 23 Sep 2020 12:46:09 EDT</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/09/200923124609.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Sodium-ion batteries are a valid alternative to Lithium-ion batteries</title>
			<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/09/200922102424.htm</link>
			<description>A team of scientists combined their knowledge and expertise to assess the current status of the Na-ion technology from materials to cell development, offering a realistic comparison of the key performance indicators for NBs and LIBs. <!-- more --></description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 22 Sep 2020 10:24:24 EDT</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/09/200922102424.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Scientists identify solid electrolyte materials that boost lithium-ion battery performance</title>
			<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/09/200922092117.htm</link>
			<description>The discovery could help battery researchers design the first solid electrolytes that are safe, cheap and efficient. <!-- more --></description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 22 Sep 2020 09:21:17 EDT</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/09/200922092117.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>New discovery to have huge impact on development of future battery cathodes</title>
			<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/09/200921111711.htm</link>
			<description>A new article reveals how researchers fully identified the nature of oxidized oxygen in the important battery material - Li-rich NMC - using RIXS (Resonant Inelastic X-ray Scattering). This compound is being closely considered for implementation in next generation Li-ion batteries because it delivers higher energy density than current materials, and could translate to longer driving ranges for electric vehicles and enable scientists to tackle issues like battery longevity and voltage fade. <!-- more --></description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 21 Sep 2020 11:17:11 EDT</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/09/200921111711.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Fast calculation dials in better batteries</title>
			<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/09/200916131029.htm</link>
			<description>A simpler and more efficient way to predict the performance of batteries will lead to better batteries, according to engineers. <!-- more --></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 16 Sep 2020 13:10:29 EDT</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/09/200916131029.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Predicting the slow death of lithium-ion batteries</title>
			<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/09/200914172928.htm</link>
			<description>A new model offers a way to predict the condition of a battery&#039;s internal systems in real-time with far more accuracy than existing tools. In electric cars, the technology could improve driving range estimates and prolong battery life. <!-- more --></description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 14 Sep 2020 17:29:28 EDT</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/09/200914172928.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Scientists probe the chemistry of a single battery electrode particle both inside and out</title>
			<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/09/200908200511.htm</link>
			<description>Cracks and chemical reactions on a battery particle&#039;s surface can degrade performance, and the particle&#039;s ability to absorb and release lithium ions also changes over time. Scientists stuck a single particle the size of a red blood cell to the tip of a microscopic needle and probed it with X-rays to see how interior and surface changes influence each other. <!-- more --></description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 08 Sep 2020 20:05:11 EDT</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/09/200908200511.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Recharging N95 masks for continued usage</title>
			<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/09/200908113241.htm</link>
			<description>In a new article, researchers share a method to restore the filtration efficiency of N95 masks to out-of-box levels, as long as the mask is not structurally compromised. <!-- more --></description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 08 Sep 2020 11:32:41 EDT</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/09/200908113241.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Battery-free Game Boy runs forever</title>
			<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/09/200903171445.htm</link>
			<description>Researchers develop first-ever battery-free, energy-harvesting, interactive device. And it looks and feels like a retro 8-bit Nintendo Game Boy. <!-- more --></description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2020 17:14:45 EDT</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/09/200903171445.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>New anode material could lead to safer fast-charging batteries</title>
			<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/09/200902114443.htm</link>
			<description>Scientists have discovered a new anode material that enables lithium-ion batteries to be safely recharged within minutes for thousands of cycles. Known as a disordered rocksalt, the new anode is made up of earth-abundant lithium, vanadium and oxygen atoms arranged in a similar way as ordinary kitchen table salt, but randomly. It is promising for commercial applications where both high energy density and high power are desired, such as electric cars, vacuum cleaners or drills. <!-- more --></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2020 11:44:43 EDT</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/09/200902114443.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Decades-old mystery of lithium-ion battery storage solved</title>
			<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/09/200902095138.htm</link>
			<description>For years, researchers have aimed to learn more about a group of metal oxides that show promise as key materials for the next generation of lithium-ion batteries because of their mysterious ability to store significantly more energy than should be possible. An international research team has now cracked the code of this scientific anomaly, knocking down a barrier to building ultra-fast battery energy storage systems. <!-- more --></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2020 09:51:38 EDT</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/09/200902095138.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>How dangerous are burning electric cars?</title>
			<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/09/200901112208.htm</link>
			<description>What happens if an electric car burns in a road tunnel or an underground car park? In the Hagerbach test tunnel in Switzerland, researchers and tunnel safety experts set fire to battery cells of electric cars, analyzed the distribution of soot and smoke gases and the chemical residues in the extinguishing water. <!-- more --></description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2020 11:22:08 EDT</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/09/200901112208.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Scientists use fruit peel to turn old batteries into new</title>
			<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/08/200826101623.htm</link>
			<description>Scientists have developed a novel method of using fruit peel waste to extract and reuse precious metals from spent lithium-ion batteries in order to create new batteries. The scientists say that their waste-to-resource approach tackles both food waste and electronics waste, supporting the development of a circular economy with zero waste. <!-- more --></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 26 Aug 2020 10:16:23 EDT</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/08/200826101623.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Thin layer protects battery, allows cold charging</title>
			<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/08/200826083031.htm</link>
			<description>In the search for a reliable, quick-charging, cold-weather battery for automobiles, a self-assembling, thin layer of electrochemically active molecules may be the solution, according to a team or researchers. <!-- more --></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 26 Aug 2020 08:30:31 EDT</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/08/200826083031.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>New insights into lithium-ion battery failure mechanism</title>
			<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/08/200825110721.htm</link>
			<description>Researchers have identified a potential new degradation mechanism for electric vehicle batteries - a key step to designing effective methods to improve battery lifespan. <!-- more --></description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 25 Aug 2020 11:07:21 EDT</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/08/200825110721.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Battery life for wearable electronic devices could be improved</title>
			<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/08/200825110654.htm</link>
			<description>Researchers have found that asymmetric stresses within electrodes used in certain wearable electronic devices provides an important clue as to how to improve the durability and lifespan of these batteries. <!-- more --></description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 25 Aug 2020 11:06:54 EDT</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/08/200825110654.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Faster, more efficient energy storage could stem from holistic study of layered materials</title>
			<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/08/200825110650.htm</link>
			<description>A team has developed a novel, integrated approach to track energy-transporting ions within an ultra-thin material, which could unlock its energy storage potential leading toward faster charging, longer lasting devices. <!-- more --></description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 25 Aug 2020 11:06:50 EDT</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/08/200825110650.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>No more playing with fire: Study offers insight into &#039;safer&#039; rechargeable batteries</title>
			<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/08/200820110910.htm</link>
			<description>Lithium-ion batteries are used in various electronic devices. But, they also come with potential hazards, particularly if the battery is damaged or overcharged. This usually occurs because, in its overcharged state, spiky structures called &#039;lithium dendrites&#039; get deposited in the battery. Now, scientists use a technique called &#039;operando nuclear magnetic resonance&#039; to track the precise mechanism of dendrite formation. They also extend their experiments to sodium-ion batteries, making their practical application easier. <!-- more --></description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 20 Aug 2020 11:09:10 EDT</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/08/200820110910.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Biomorphic batteries could provide 72 times more energy for robots</title>
			<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/08/200819144111.htm</link>
			<description>Like biological fat reserves store energy in animals, a new rechargeable zinc battery integrates into the structure of a robot to provide much more energy, researchers have shown. <!-- more --></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 19 Aug 2020 14:41:11 EDT</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/08/200819144111.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Upcycling plastic waste toward sustainable energy storage</title>
			<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/08/200812115322.htm</link>
			<description>Engineering professors and their students have been working for years on creating improved energy storage materials from sustainable sources, such as glass bottles, beach sand, Silly Putty, and portabella mushrooms. Now they have turned plastic soda bottles into a nanomaterial for use in batteries. Though they don&#039;t store as much energy as lithium-ion batteries, supercapacitors made with the material can charge much faster. <!-- more --></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2020 11:53:22 EDT</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/08/200812115322.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Analysis of renewable energy points toward more affordable carbon-free electricity</title>
			<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/08/200806133513.htm</link>
			<description>A study identifies long-term storage technologies that would enhance the affordability and reliability of renewable electricity. <!-- more --></description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2020 13:35:13 EDT</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/08/200806133513.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Anode material for safe batteries with a long cycle life</title>
			<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/08/200806111828.htm</link>
			<description>Researchers investigated a highly promising anode material for future high-performance batteries - lithium lanthanum titanate with a perovskite crystal structure (LLTO). Researchers can improve the energy density, power density, charging rate, safety, and cycle life of batteries without requiring a decrease of the particle size from micro to nano scale. <!-- more --></description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2020 11:18:28 EDT</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/08/200806111828.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Battery breakthrough gives boost to electric flight and long-range electric cars</title>
			<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/07/200720102044.htm</link>
			<description>Researchers have developed a new battery material that could enable long-range electric vehicles that can drive for hundreds of miles on a single charge, and electric planes called eVTOLs for fast, environmentally friendly commutes. <!-- more --></description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 20 Jul 2020 10:20:44 EDT</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/07/200720102044.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Researchers create a roadmap to better multivalent batteries</title>
			<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/07/200717133238.htm</link>
			<description>Lithium-ion batteries power everything from mobile phones to laptop computers and electric vehicles, but demand is growing for less expensive and more readily available alternatives. The top candidates all hold promise, but researchers report that steep challenges remain. <!-- more --></description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 17 Jul 2020 13:32:38 EDT</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/07/200717133238.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>New cobalt-free lithium-ion battery reduces costs without sacrificing performance</title>
			<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/07/200716101612.htm</link>
			<description>Researchers say they&#039;ve cracked the code to a cobalt-free high-energy lithium-ion battery, eliminating the cobalt and opening the door to reducing the costs of producing batteries while boosting performance in some ways. <!-- more --></description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 16 Jul 2020 10:16:12 EDT</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/07/200716101612.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>A GoPro for beetles: Researchers create a robotic camera backpack for insects</title>
			<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/07/200715142253.htm</link>
			<description>Researchers have developed a tiny camera that can ride aboard an insect or an insect-sized robot. <!-- more --></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 15 Jul 2020 14:22:53 EDT</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/07/200715142253.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>New lithium battery charges faster, reduces risk of device explosions</title>
			<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/07/200714182148.htm</link>
			<description>Cell phone batteries often heat up and, at times, can burst into flames. In most cases, the culprit behind such incidents can be traced back to lithium batteries. Despite providing long-lasting electric currents that can keep devices powered up, lithium batteries can internally short circuit, heating up the device. <!-- more --></description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2020 18:21:48 EDT</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/07/200714182148.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Tale of the tape: Sticky bits make better batteries</title>
			<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/07/200714121746.htm</link>
			<description>Scientists use an industrial laser to turn adhesive tape into a component for safer, anode-free lithium metal batteries. <!-- more --></description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2020 12:17:46 EDT</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/07/200714121746.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>New room-temperature liquid-metal battery could be the path to powering the future</title>
			<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/07/200706173442.htm</link>
			<description>Researchers have created a new liquid battery with components that can remain molten at room temperature. Other liquid batteries must be kept at 240 degrees Celsius for their components to stay molten. <!-- more --></description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 06 Jul 2020 17:34:42 EDT</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/07/200706173442.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>AI could help improve performance of lithium-ion batteries and fuel cells</title>
			<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/06/200625080942.htm</link>
			<description>Researchers have demonstrated how machine learning could help design lithium-ion batteries and fuel cells with better performance. <!-- more --></description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 25 Jun 2020 08:09:42 EDT</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/06/200625080942.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Nature-imitating coating makes batteries more durable and efficient</title>
			<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/06/200624120445.htm</link>
			<description>Researchers have made use of carbon dioxide in the production of a battery protective coating. In the future, the coating could multiply the battery life and enable the use of new, more efficient materials. <!-- more --></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 24 Jun 2020 12:04:45 EDT</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/06/200624120445.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>New battery electrolyte may boost the performance of electric vehicles</title>
			<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/06/200622133016.htm</link>
			<description>Researchers have designed a new electrolyte for lithium metal batteries that could increase the driving range of electric cars. <!-- more --></description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 22 Jun 2020 13:30:16 EDT</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/06/200622133016.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Researchers make next-generation, high-toughness battery component</title>
			<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/06/200618124801.htm</link>
			<description>By combining a ceramic material with graphene, engineers have made what they say is the toughest solid electrolyte built to date. <!-- more --></description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 18 Jun 2020 12:48:01 EDT</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/06/200618124801.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Two-dimensional carbon networks</title>
			<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/06/200618102412.htm</link>
			<description>Lithium-ion batteries usually contain graphitic carbons as anode materials. Scientists have investigated the carbonic nanoweb graphdiyne as a novel two-dimensional carbon network for its suitability in battery applications. Graphdiyne is as flat and thin as graphene, which is the one-atomic-layer-thin version of graphite, but it has a higher porosity and adjustable electronic properties. Researchers now describe its simple bottom-up synthesis from tailor-made precursor molecules. <!-- more --></description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 18 Jun 2020 10:24:12 EDT</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/06/200618102412.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Engineers develop new fuel cells with twice the operating voltage as hydrogen</title>
			<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/06/200618092445.htm</link>
			<description>Engineers have developed high-power, direct borohydride fuel cells that operate at double the voltage of conventional hydrogen fuel cells. <!-- more --></description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 18 Jun 2020 09:24:45 EDT</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/06/200618092445.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Using the game &#039;Jenga&#039; to explain lithium-ion batteries</title>
			<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/06/200615140841.htm</link>
			<description>Tower block games such as Jenga can be used to explain to schoolchildren how lithium-ion batteries work, meeting an educational need to better understand a power source that has become vital to everyday life. <!-- more --></description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 15 Jun 2020 14:08:41 EDT</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/06/200615140841.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Water vapor in the atmosphere may be prime renewable energy source</title>
			<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/06/200609122912.htm</link>
			<description>A new study finds that water vapor in the atmosphere may serve as a potential renewable energy source in the future. <!-- more --></description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 09 Jun 2020 12:29:12 EDT</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/06/200609122912.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Spontaneous formation of nanoscale hollow structures could boost battery storage</title>
			<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/06/200609104233.htm</link>
			<description>An unexpected property of nanometer-scale antimony crystals -- the spontaneous formation of hollow structures -- could help give the next generation of lithium ion batteries higher energy density without reducing battery lifetime. The reversibly hollowing structures could allow lithium ion batteries to hold more energy and therefore provide more power between charges. <!-- more --></description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 09 Jun 2020 10:42:33 EDT</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/06/200609104233.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Tiny, magnetically powered neural stimulator</title>
			<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/06/200608132537.htm</link>
			<description>Neuroengineers have created a tiny surgical implant that can electrically stimulate the brain and nervous system without using a battery or wired power supply. <!-- more --></description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 08 Jun 2020 13:25:37 EDT</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/06/200608132537.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Breaking the mold: An unusual choice of material yields incredibly long-lasting batteries</title>
			<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/06/200603132522.htm</link>
			<description>Scientists have developed a novel silica-based cathode for lithium-sulfur batteries, thereby enabling the realization of batteries that can last for over 2000 charge/discharge cycles. The possibility of successfully using the unconventional silica could spark a paradigm shift in rechargeable battery designs. <!-- more --></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 03 Jun 2020 13:25:22 EDT</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/06/200603132522.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>New NiMH batteries perform better when made from recycled old NiMH batteries</title>
			<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/06/200601120034.htm</link>
			<description>A new method for recycling old batteries can provide better performing and cheaper rechargeable hydride batteries (NiMH) as shown in a new study. <!-- more --></description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 12:00:34 EDT</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/06/200601120034.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Researchers develop viable sodium battery</title>
			<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/06/200601072951.htm</link>
			<description>Researchers have created a sodium-ion battery that holds as much energy and works as well as some commercial lithium-ion battery chemistries, making for a potentially viable battery technology out of abundant and cheap materials. The team reports one of the best results to date for a sodium-ion battery. <!-- more --></description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 07:29:51 EDT</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/06/200601072951.htm</guid>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
<!-- Page successfully written to cache. -->
